<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn</id>
    <title>纽约时报中文网 | 纽约时报官网网址</title>
    <updated>2021-01-17T02:48:24.933Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>纽约时报中文网app, 纽约时报官网网址</subtitle>
    <logo>https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2021, 纽约时报中文网 | 纽约时报官网网址</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[关于总统就职日，你需要知道的七个关键问题]]></title>
        <id>https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/post/02zx983/</id>
        <link href="https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/post/02zx983/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-17T02:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>关于总统就职日，你需要知道的七个关键问题<br>
Inauguration Day: What You Need to Know<br>
AISHVARYA KAVI<br>
2021年1月15日</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/post-images/1610848886451.webp" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Joseph R. Biden Jr. will become president of the United States at noon on Jan. 20 in a scaled-back inauguration ceremony. While key elements will remain traditional, many events will be downsized and “reimagined” to better adapt the celebration to a nation battling the coronavirus. Here’s a guide to the event.</p>
<p>小约瑟夫·R·拜登(Joseph R. Biden Jr.)将于1月20日中午在一个缩减规模的就职典礼上成为美国总统。尽管关键元素仍将保持传统，但许多活动将被缩减和“重新设计”，以便更好地适应这个正在抗击新冠的国家。以下是典礼的指南。</p>
<p><strong>What will the inauguration look like?<br>
就职典礼将会是什么样？</strong></p>
<p>Although many of the events will be virtual, Maju Varghese, the executive director of the Presidential Inaugural Committee, said the goal was an “inclusive and accessible celebration that brings Americans together and unifies our nation, especially during such a tough time for our country.”</p>
<p>尽管很多活动都在网上举行，但总统就职委员会执行主任马祖·瓦尔盖塞(Maju Varghese)说，目标是“一场包容性强、平易近人的庆祝活动，让美国人团结起来，让我们的国家团结起来，尤其是在我们国家如此艰难的时期”。</p>
<p>Mr. Biden will be sworn in by Chief Justice John G. Roberts Jr. on the Capitol’s West Front sometime before noon. The new president is then expected to give his inaugural address and conduct a review of military troops, as is tradition.</p>
<p>中午之前，拜登将在首席大法官小约翰·G·罗伯茨(John G. Roberts Jr.)主持下，在国会大厦西面宣誓就职。随后，按照传统，新总统将发表就职演说并检阅军队。</p>
<p>But instead of a traditional parade before cheering spectators along Pennsylvania Avenue as the new president, vice president and their families make their way to the White House over a mile away, there will be an official escort with representatives from every branch of the military for one city block.</p>
<p>但是，当新任总统、副总统和他们的家人前往一英里外的白宫时，出现在宾夕法尼亚大道上欢呼的观众面前的，将不是传统的游行，而是一个城市街区的官方护卫队，由各军种的代表组成。</p>
<p>For remote viewers, the inaugural committee has planned what it is calling a virtual parade across the country featuring music, poets and dancers “paying homage to America’s heroes on the front lines of the pandemic.”</p>
<p>就职典礼委员会计划为全国范围的远程观众举行一场网上游行，包括音乐、诗人和舞蹈者，“向在疫情前线的美国英雄们致敬”。</p>
<p>At 5:30 p.m. Tuesday, the evening before Mr. Biden takes the oath, the committee will hold a lighting ceremony around the Lincoln Memorial Reflecting Pool in remembrance of people in the United States who have lost their lives in the coronavirus pandemic.</p>
<p>周二下午5点30分，也就是拜登宣誓就职的前一晚，该委员会将在林肯纪念堂倒影池周围举行点灯仪式，纪念在新冠病毒大流行中丧生的美国人。</p>
<p><strong>Wait, is Tom Hanks going to be there?<br>
等等，汤姆·汉克斯(Tom Hanks)也会去吗？</strong></p>
<p>Instead of the usual balls after the ceremony feting the new president, there will be a prime-time television event at 8:30 p.m. Wednesday evening hosted by Tom Hanks and featuring celebrities including Justin Timberlake, Demi Lovato, Ant Clemons and Jon Bon Jovi.</p>
<p>新总统就职典礼后，不是通常的舞会，而是在周三晚上8点30举办一场黄金时段电视活动，由汤姆·汉克斯主持，出席的明星包括贾斯汀·汀布莱克(Justin Timberlake)、黛米·洛瓦托(Demi Lovato)、安特·克莱蒙斯(Ant Clemons)和乔·邦·乔维(Jon Bon Jovi)。</p>
<p>Two major celebrities will participate in the swearing-in ceremony: Lady Gaga will sing the national anthem and Jennifer Lopez will give a musical performance.</p>
<p>两位明星将参加宣誓仪式：Lady Gaga将演唱国歌，詹妮弗·洛佩兹(Jennifer Lopez)将献唱。</p>
<p><strong>Is there expected to be unrest?<br>
预计会发生动乱吗？</strong></p>
<p>For weeks, Washington has been preparing for the possibility of protesters. But the nation’s capital was kicked into high alert after a violent mob breached the Capitol building and forced lawmakers to halt the official counting of Electoral College votes to affirm Mr. Biden’s victory.</p>
<p>几周来，华盛顿一直在为可能出现的抗议者做准备。但在一群暴徒冲进国会大厦，迫使议员们停止正式清点选举人票以确认拜登获胜后，首都进入了高度戒备状态。</p>
<p>Mayor Muriel E. Bowser has warned that extremists who support Mr. Trump might continue to wreak havoc and she extended the city’s public emergency through Jan. 21.</p>
<p>市长穆丽尔·E·鲍泽(Muriel E. Bowser)警告，支持特朗普的极端分子可能会继续造成破坏，她将该市的公共紧急状态延长至1月21日。</p>
<p>The F.B.I. and Secret Service have ramped up security efforts around the inauguration. Experts have warned that some far-right extremist groups are already discussing an assault on Inauguration Day similar to the deadly attack on the Capitol.</p>
<p>联邦调查局和特勤局加强了就职典礼前后的安保。专家警告说，一些极右极端组织已开始讨论在就职日发动类似国会大厦致命袭击的行动。</p>
<p>Unrest on Inauguration Day is not unprecedented: During Mr. Trump’s inauguration in 2017, crowds in Washington damaged storefronts, threw rocks and bricks at police officers and lit a limousine on fire in protest of Mr. Trump’s election. The day ended in more than 200 arrests.</p>
<p>就职日发生骚乱并非史无前例：在2017年特朗普就职典礼期间，华盛顿的人群破坏店面，向警察投掷石块和砖块，并点燃一辆豪华轿车，以抗议特朗普当选。当天有200多人被捕。</p>
<p><strong>Will President Trump attend?<br>
特朗普总统会出席吗？</strong></p>
<p>President Trump announced Friday that he would not attend Mr. Biden’s inauguration.</p>
<p>特朗普总统周五宣布，他不会参加拜登的就职典礼。</p>
<p>Mr. Biden called that decision “one of the few things he and I have ever agreed on.”</p>
<p>拜登称这一决定是“他和我仅有的几件达成一致的事之一”。</p>
<p>Still, it is a major break with tradition for a president to skip the ceremonial heart of the country’s democracy: the peaceful transfer of power.</p>
<p>尽管如此，对于一位总统来说，跳过该国民主的礼仪核心：权力的和平交接，仍然是对传统的一次重大背离。</p>
<p>Vice President Mike Pence will attend, an aide said Saturday, after Mr. Biden made clear on Friday that he was welcome.</p>
<p>副总统迈克·彭斯(Mike Pence)的一名助手周六表示彭斯将出席，此前拜登周五明确表示欢迎他出席。</p>
<p>Only three presidents have missed their successor’s swearing-in: John Adams in 1801, his son John Quincy Adams in 1829 and Andrew Johnson, a Democrat who sat out the 1869 inauguration after he was replaced in favor of a Republican, Ulysses S. Grant.</p>
<p>只有三位总统错过了继任者的就职典礼：1801年的约翰·亚当斯(John Adams)；1829年，他的儿子约翰·昆西·亚当斯(John Quincy Adams)；以及民主党人安德鲁·约翰逊(Andrew Johnson)，他被共和党人尤利西斯-格兰特取代，于是缺席了后者1869年的就职典礼。</p>
<p><strong>Who will be there?<br>
谁会去？</strong></p>
<p>George W. Bush, has confirmed he would travel to Washington for Inauguration Day, along with Laura Bush, the former first lady. Barack Obama and Bill Clinton are also expected to attend, along with former first ladies Michelle Obama and Hillary Clinton. Jimmy Carter, who at 96 is the oldest living former president, announced that he and his wife would not attend. It will be the first presidential inauguration Mr. Carter has missed since he was sworn in.</p>
<p>乔治·W·布什(George W. Bush)已经证实，他将和前第一夫人劳拉·布什(Laura Bush)一起前往华盛顿参加就职典礼。预计贝拉克·奥巴马(Barack Obam)和比尔·克林顿(Bill Clinton)，以及前第一夫人米歇尔·奥巴马(Michelle Obama)和希拉里·克林顿(Hillary Clinton)也将出席。96岁的吉米·卡特(Jimmy Carter)是在世的前总统中最年长的一位，他宣布他和妻子不会出席。这将是卡特宣誓就职以来首次缺席总统就职典礼。</p>
<p><strong>Can I attend?<br>
我可以参加吗？</strong></p>
<p>No. Traditionally, the Joint Congressional Committee on Inaugural Ceremonies would distribute hundreds of thousands of tickets to the swearing-in ceremony for members of Congress to invite constituents, but this year tickets are not available to members of the public. Planners are urging people to stay home and participate in virtual inaugural events to prevent large crowds that could easily spread the coronavirus.</p>
<p>不行。传统上，国会就职典礼联合委员会(Joint Congressional Committee on就职典礼)会向国会议员分发数十万张就职典礼的入场券，让他们邀请选民参加，但今年的入场券不向公众开放。策划人员敦促人们待在家里，在网上观看就职活动，以防止大量人群聚集传播新冠病毒。</p>
<p>Events will be live streamed by the Presidential Inaugural Committee and by The New York Times.</p>
<p>活动将由总统就职委员会和《纽约时报》进行网络直播。</p>
<p><strong>Why is a presidential inauguration so important?<br>
为什么总统就职典礼这么重要？</strong></p>
<p>The 20th Amendment to the Constitution requires that the term of each elected president and vice president begin at noon Jan. 20 of the year after the election. Every president has taken the oath of office, and they cannot assume their positions without doing so.</p>
<p>宪法第20条修正案要求，每一位候任总统和副总统的任期从选举后的1月20日中午开始。每一位总统都需宣誓就职，未经宣誓不得就职。</p>
<p>Symbolically, it marks the peaceful transfer of power from the current president to the next. Inauguration Day will be all the more important this year, as Mr. Biden ascends to the presidency at a time when political division has threatened the nation’s democratic institutions and his predecessor has gone to extreme lengths to stay in power.</p>
<p>从象征意义上讲，它标志着权力从现任总统和平地移交给下一任总统。今年的就职日将更加重要，因为拜登升任总统之际，政治分歧已经威胁到美国的民主制度，而他的前任为了保住权力不惜铤而走险。</p>
<p>The inauguration is also a notable fund-raising opportunity for the incoming president. Though traditional events like balls have been canceled, Mr. Biden’s inaugural committee is offering special “V.I.P. participation” to corporations and well-heeled individuals who can use the opportunity to curry favor with the new administration.</p>
<p>就职典礼对即将上任的总统来说也是一个重要的筹款机会。虽然舞会等传统活动已被取消，但拜登的就职典礼委员会为企业和富豪提供了特别的“贵宾参与”机会，他们可以借此机会讨好新政府。</p>
<p>Excess donations cannot be transferred to federal campaigns or party committees. Past inaugural committees have given unspent funds to charities for disaster relief as well as groups that decorate and maintain the White House and the vice president’s residence.</p>
<p>多余的捐款不能转移到联邦竞选活动或政党委员会。以往的就职委员会都会将未使用的资金捐给救灾慈善机构，以及负责装饰和维护白宫和副总统官邸的团体。</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[关于特朗普遭第二次弹劾，目前我们所知道的]]></title>
        <id>https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/post/WGNsnmyGk/</id>
        <link href="https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/post/WGNsnmyGk/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-14T02:08:20.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>关于特朗普遭第二次弹劾，目前我们所知道的<br>
Why Remove Trump Now? A Guide to the Second Impeachment of a President<br>
CATIE EDMONDSON<br>
2021年1月14日</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/post-images/1610849362880.webp" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>WASHINGTON — The House on Wednesday impeached President Trump for a second time, a first in American history, charging him with “incitement of insurrection” one week after he egged on a mob of supporters that stormed the Capitol while Congress met to formalize President-elect Joseph R. Biden Jr.’s victory.</p>
<p>华盛顿——周三，众议院以“煽动叛乱”为由第二次弹劾特朗普总统，这在美国历史上尚属首次。此前一周，特朗普怂恿一群支持者冲击国会大厦，当时国会正在开会确认候任总统小约瑟夫·R·拜登(Joseph R. Biden Jr.)的选举胜利。</p>
<p>Democrats have moved swiftly to impeach Mr. Trump after the assault, which unfolded after he told supporters at a rally near the National Mall to march on the Capitol in an effort to get Republicans to overturn his defeat. At least five people, including a Capitol Police officer, died during the siege and in the immediate aftermath.</p>
<p>特朗普在国家广场附近的一场集会上告诉支持者向着国会大厦游行，以便让共和党人推翻他的失败，随后发生了袭击事件。至少五人在围攻过程中及之后死亡，包括一名国会警察。袭击发生后，民主党迅速对特朗普启动弹劾程序。</p>
<p>The process is taking place with extraordinary speed and testing the bounds of the impeachment process, raising questions never contemplated before. Here’s what we know.</p>
<p>程序以非同寻常的速度进行，考验了弹劾程序本身的边界，引发了人们从未考虑过的问题。以下是我们所知道的情况。</p>
<p><strong>Impeachment is one of the Constitution’s gravest penalties.<br>
弹劾是宪法最严厉的惩罚之一。</strong></p>
<p>Impeachment is one of the weightiest tools the Constitution gives Congress to hold government officials, including the president, accountable for misconduct and abuse of power.</p>
<p>弹劾是宪法赋予国会的最重要的工具之一，用以追究包括总统在内的政府官员的不当行为和滥用权力的责任。</p>
<p>Members of the House consider whether to impeach the president — the equivalent of an indictment in a criminal case — and members of the Senate consider whether to remove him, holding a trial in which senators act as the jury. The test, as set by the Constitution, is whether the president has committed “treason, bribery, or other high crimes and misdemeanors.”</p>
<p>众议院成员决定是否弹劾总统——相当于刑事案件中的起诉——参议院成员决定是否罢免总统，举行一场由参议员担任陪审团的审判。按照宪法的规定，裁定总统是否犯有“叛国罪、受贿罪或其他重大罪行和不当行为”。</p>
<p>The House vote requires only a simple majority of lawmakers to agree that the president has, in fact, committed high crimes and misdemeanors; the Senate vote requires a two-thirds majority.</p>
<p>众议院投票只需要简单多数议员同意总统实际上犯有重大罪行和不当行为；参议院的投票需要三分之二多数。</p>
<p><strong>The charge against Trump is ‘incitement of insurrection.’<br>
对特朗普的指控是“煽动叛乱”。</strong></p>
<p>The article, drafted by Representatives David Cicilline of Rhode Island, Ted Lieu of California, Jamie Raskin of Maryland and Jerrold Nadler of New York, charged Mr. Trump with “incitement of insurrection,” saying he is guilty of “inciting violence against the government of the United States.”</p>
<p>弹劾书由罗德岛州众议员戴维·西西林(David Cicilline)、加利福尼亚州众议员刘云平(Ted Lieu)、马里兰州众议员杰米·拉斯金(Jamie Raskin)和纽约州众议员杰罗尔德·纳德勒(Jerrold Nadler)起草，指控特朗普“煽动叛乱”，称他“煽动针对美国政府的暴力”。</p>
<p>The article cited Mr. Trump’s weekslong campaign to falsely discredit the results of the November election, and it quotes directly from the speech he gave on the day of the siege in which he told his supporters to go to the Capitol. “If you don’t fight like hell,” he said, “you’re not going to have a country anymore.”</p>
<p>弹劾书引用了特朗普数周以来诋毁11月选举结果的宣传活动，并直接引用了他在围攻事件当天的演讲，他在演讲中告诉支持者去国会大厦。“如果你不拼命战斗，”他说，“你将不再拥有这个国家。”</p>
<p>Proponents say impeachment is worthwhile even though Trump has only days left in office.</p>
<p>弹劾的支持者表示，尽管特朗普的任期只剩几天，弹劾还是值得的。</p>
<p>While the House moved with remarkable speed to impeach Mr. Trump, the Senate trial to determine whether to remove him cannot begin until Jan. 19, his final full day in office. That means any conviction would almost certainly not be completed until after he leaves the White House.</p>
<p>虽然众议院以惊人的速度弹劾特朗普，但参议院决定是否罢免他的审判要到1月19日才会开始，那是特朗普在任的最后一天。几乎可以肯定的是，这意味着任何定罪要在他离开白宫后才能完成。</p>
<p>Democrats have argued that Mr. Trump’s offense — using his power as the nation’s leader and commander in chief to incite an insurrection against the legislative branch — is so grave that it must be addressed, even with just a few days remaining in his term. To let it go unpunished, Democrats argued, would set a dangerous precedent of impunity for future presidents.</p>
<p>民主党人认为，特朗普利用他作为国家领导人和三军统帅的权力煽动反对立法部门的叛乱，罪行非常严重，必须予以处理，即使他的任期只剩几天。民主党人认为，如果放任的话，将为未来的总统树立一个有罪不罚的危险先例。</p>
<p>“Is there little time left?” Representative Steny H. Hoyer, Democrat of Maryland and the majority leader, said during the debate. “Yes. But it is never too late to do the right thing.”</p>
<p>“时间不多了吗？”马里兰州民主党众议员、多数党领袖斯坦尼·H·霍耶(Steny H. Hoyer)在辩论中说。“是的。但做正确的事，什么时候都不算晚。”</p>
<p>Republicans, many of whom voted to overturn the election results, have claimed that going through the impeachment process so late in Mr. Trump’s term will foster unnecessary division and that the country should move on from last week’s siege.</p>
<p>共和党人声称，在特朗普的任期已经到了这么晚的时候再走弹劾程序，会助长不必要的分裂，国家应该从上周的围攻事件中走出来，继续前进。他们当中很多人投票推翻选举结果。</p>
<p><strong>The biggest consequence for Trump could be disqualifying him from holding office again.<br>
对特朗普而言，最严重的后果可能是剥夺他再次担任公职的资格。</strong></p>
<p>Conviction in an impeachment trial would not automatically disqualify Mr. Trump from future public office. But if the Senate were to convict him, the Constitution allows a subsequent vote to bar an official from holding “any office of honor, trust or profit under the United States.”</p>
<p>在弹劾审判中被定罪不会自动取消特朗普在未来担任公职的资格。但是如果参议院要对他定罪，那么宪法允许随后进行投票以剥夺官员担任“合众国属下有荣誉、有责任或有薪金的任何职务的资格”。</p>
<p>That vote would require only a simple majority of senators. Such a step could be an appealing prospect not just to Democrats, but also to many Republicans who either have set their sights on the presidency themselves or are convinced that it is the only thing that will purge Mr. Trump from their party. Senator Mitch McConnell of Kentucky, the Republican leader, is said to hold the latter view.</p>
<p>该投票只需要参议员的简单多数即可。这前景不仅对民主党人具有吸引力，而且对许多共和党人来说也具有吸引力——他们要么想自己坐上总统的位子，要么坚信这是唯一可以将特朗普从党内清除的办法。共和党领袖肯塔基州参议员麦康奈尔(Mitch McConnell)据说持后一种观点。</p>
<p>There is no precedent, however, for disqualifying a president from future office, and the issue could end up before the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>但是，还没有剥夺总统任未来公职资格的先例，这个问题可能会面临最高法院的裁决。</p>
<p><strong>The Senate trial most won’t start until after Biden becomes president.<br>
参议院的审判不会在拜登担任总统之前开始。</strong></p>
<p>Democrats who control the House can choose when to send their article of impeachment to the Senate, at which point that chamber would have to immediately move to begin the trial. But because the Senate is not scheduled to hold a regular session until Jan. 19, even if the House immediately transmitted the charge to the other side of the Capitol, an agreement between Senate Republican and Democratic leaders would be needed to take it up before then.</p>
<p>控制众议院的民主党人可以选择何时将弹劾书送交参议院，届时参议院必须立即采取行动开始审判。但是由于参议院在1月19日前没有事先安排的例会，即使众议院立即将指控交予参议院，仍需要参议院的共和党和民主党领导人在那之前达成一致以开展工作。</p>
<p>Mr. McConnell said on Wednesday that he would not agree to do so, meaning that the article could not be taken up until the day before Mr. Biden is sworn in. Since time is needed for the Senate to set the rules for an impeachment trial, that means the proceeding probably would not start until after Mr. Biden was president, and Democrats had operational control of the Senate.</p>
<p>麦康奈尔周三表示不同意这样做，这意味着在拜登宣誓就职之前不能开始处理弹劾书。因为参议院需要时间来制定弹劾审判的规则，这意味着程序可能要等到拜登担任总统之后才开始，而届时参议院的运转也将由民主党控制。</p>
<p>“Given the rules, procedures, and Senate precedents that govern presidential impeachment trials, there is simply no chance that a fair or serious trial could conclude before President-elect Biden is sworn in next week,” Mr. McConnell said. “In light of this reality, I believe it will best serve our nation if Congress and the executive branch spend the next seven days completely focused on facilitating a safe inauguration and an orderly transfer of power to the incoming Biden administration.”</p>
<p>“鉴于总统弹劾审判的规则、程序和参议院先例，在候任总统拜登下周宣誓前，是没有机会完成一场公正或严肃的审判的，”麦康奈尔说。“鉴于这种现实，我认为，如果国会和行政部门用接下来的七天专注于促进总统就职典礼的安全以及将权力有序地移交给即将上任的拜登政府，那将符合我国的最大利益。”</p>
<p><strong>The trial could consume the Senate during Biden’s first days in office.<br>
在拜登任职的最初几天，该审判可能会消耗参议院的全部时间。</strong></p>
<p>Once the Senate receives the impeachment charge, it must immediately take up the issue, as articles of impeachment carry the highest privilege. Under rules in place for decades, impeachment is the only issue the Senate can consider while a trial is underway; it cannot simultaneously consider other legislative business.</p>
<p>一旦参议院收到弹劾指控，必须马上处理该问题，因为弹劾条款享有最高优先级。根据几十年来的既有规定，在弹劾审判期间参议院唯一可以考虑的只有弹劾的问题。它不能同时考虑其他立法事务。</p>
<p>But Mr. Biden has asked Mr. McConnell whether it would be possible to alter that rule, allowing the Senate to conduct Mr. Trump’s impeachment trial on a parallel track to consideration of his cabinet nominees, splitting its days between the two. Mr. McConnell told Mr. Biden he would consult with the Senate parliamentarian on whether that would be possible.</p>
<p>但是拜登已经询问麦康奈尔是否有可能改变这一规则，从而允许参议院在执行特朗普的弹劾审判的同时，进行对他的内阁提名人的确认程序，将两个程序的时间平分。麦康奈尔告诉拜登，他会与参议院议员就是否可行进行协商。</p>
<p>If such a bifurcated process were not possible, House Democrats might choose to hold back the article to allow Mr. Biden time to win confirmation of his team before a trial got underway.</p>
<p>如果不能同时进行，众议院民主党人可能会选择暂缓弹劾条款，使拜登有时间在审判开始之前赢得参议院对他的团队的确认。</p>
<p>The Senate could hold a trial for Mr. Trump even after he has left office, though there is no precedent for a president being tried after his term is over. Other government officials who were impeached have been tried after they departed.</p>
<p>参议院甚至可以在特朗普卸任后对他进行审判，尽管没有在总统任期结束后对总统进行审判的先例。有其他被弹劾的政府官员在离任后受到审判。</p>
<p>Only two presidents other than Mr. Trump have been impeached — Andrew Johnson in 1868 and Bill Clinton in 1998 — and both were ultimately acquitted and completed their terms in office.</p>
<p>除特朗普外，只有两名总统曾被弹劾——1868年的安德鲁·约翰逊和1998年的比尔·克林顿——最终都被宣判无罪，并完成了任期。</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[打扫、做饭，保持身材：韩国“孕妇指南”引众怒]]></title>
        <id>https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/post/0tc2yXn4r/</id>
        <link href="https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/post/0tc2yXn4r/">
        </link>
        <updated>2021-01-13T02:10:51.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>打扫、做饭，保持身材：韩国“孕妇指南”引众怒<br>
Seoul’s Advice to Pregnant Women: Cook, Clean and Stay Attractive<br>
LIVIA ALBECK-RIPKA, YOUMI KIM<br>
2021年1月13日</p>
<figure data-type="image" tabindex="1"><img src="https://chenglish.github.io/nytcn/post-images/1610849484489.webp" alt="" loading="lazy"></figure>
<p>Before giving birth, check that your family has sufficient toilet paper. Prepare ready-made meals for your husband, who surely “is not good at cooking.” Tie up your hair, “so that you don’t look disheveled” even as you go without a bath. And after the baby arrives, keep a “small-size” dress in sight — you’ll need motivation not to take that extra bite.</p>
<p>生孩子之前，要检查家里有没有足够的厕纸。为丈夫准备好饭菜，因为他肯定“不擅长做饭”。把头发扎起来，这样即使没有洗澡“也不会显得邋遢”。在孩子出生后，要把一件“小码”的裙子放在眼前——你需要动力来克制自己，不要多吃那一口。</p>
<p>These words of advice, offered to pregnant women by the authorities in Seoul, have created a backlash in South Korea, where the government can ill afford to fumble as it desperately tries to compel women to have more babies and reverse the world’s lowest birthrate.</p>
<p>这些首尔当局提供给孕妇的建议在韩国引起了强烈反弹。对于这个正在竭力迫使女性生更多的孩子，以扭转世界最低生育率的政府而言，这样的笨拙表现造成的后果是它难以承担的。</p>
<p>The pregnancy guidelines were first published on a government website in 2019. But they caught the attention of the public only in recent days, causing an outcry on social media, where people said they reflected outmoded views that persist in segments of the deeply patriarchal society and petitioned for their removal.</p>
<p>这份孕期指南于2019年首次在政府网站上发布。但直到最近才引起公众关注，在社交媒体上引发了强烈抗议。人们说这些指南反映了在父权制根深蒂固的社会中存在的过时观点，并且请愿要求删除它们。</p>
<p>Yong Hye-in, an activist and politician, said that under the guidelines, a woman’s child-rearing responsibilities were doubled by having to care for her husband too. A better tactic for those married to men incapable of doing things like throwing away rotting food, Ms. Yong wrote on Twitter, would be divorce.</p>
<p>活动人士和政治人士永惠英（Yong Hye-in，音）表示，根据该指导方针，女性养育孩子的责任因为还要照顾丈夫而加倍。永惠英在Twitter上写道，相比嫁给不会扔掉腐烂食物的男人，更好的策略是离婚。</p>
<p>Experts called the government’s advice a missed opportunity. “I think it is written by someone who never gave birth,” said Dr. Kim Jae-yean, chairman of the Korean Association of Obstetricians and Gynecologists. He added that the government should have provided practical advice on issues like breastfeeding.</p>
<p>专家称政府的建议错失良机。“我觉得这是从来没生过孩子的人写的，”韩国妇产科医师协会(Korean Association of Obstetricians and Gynecologists)会长金在容（Kim Jae-yean，音）医生说。他还说，政府本应就母乳喂养等问题提供实用的建议。</p>
<p>A petition started online last week, which has been signed by more than 21,000 people, called for a public apology from officials, as well as disciplinary action against those who released the guidelines.</p>
<p>上周，网上出现一份请愿书，已有超过2.1万人签名，要求官员公开道歉，并对发布指导方针者进行惩戒。</p>
<p>In an email to The New York Times, the public health division of the Seoul city government said it felt “responsible for not reviewing and monitoring the contents, approved at the time, thoroughly and closely.” It said it would review its online content, and improve gender sensitivity training for all municipal employees.</p>
<p>首尔市政府公共卫生部门在接受《纽约时报》电子邮件采访中表示，它觉得“对当时批准的内容没有进行彻底、密切的审查和监督负有责任”。该部门表示，将审查其在线内容，并改进对所有市政员工的性别敏感培训。</p>
<p>While the most offensive parts of the guidelines have been removed, some of the advice remains online, and screenshots of the original text continue to circulate on social media.</p>
<p>尽管指南中最令人反感的部分已被删除，但其中部分建议仍然保留在网上，原始文本的截图继续在社交媒体上流传。</p>
<p>“Why are we looking for the cause of the low birthrate from far away? It’s right here,” wrote one person on Twitter. Another said women were infuriated by the rules: “Who made this guideline? There are lots of things to be corrected.”</p>
<p>“为什么要从远处寻找出生率低的原因，答案就在这里，”有人在Twitter上写道。另一个人写道，女性被这些规定激怒了。“谁制定的这些规定？很多地方需要改正。”</p>
<p>Some lawmakers criticized the messaging as damaging for South Korea’s reputation.</p>
<p>一些议员批评这样的信息损害了韩国的声誉。</p>
<p>“It is awkward that the anachronistic admonition on how pregnant women should serve their families is still being distributed,” Woo Sang-ho, a lawmaker of the governing Democratic Party, wrote on Facebook last week, before the guidelines were removed.</p>
<p>“让人尴尬的是，关于孕妇应该如何为家人服务的过时警告仍在传播，”执政的民主党议员禹相虎(Woo Sang-ho)上周在Facebook上写道。该指导方针已被删除。</p>
<p>Others, however, said the online criticism went too far.</p>
<p>然而，也有人表示，网上的批评太过火了。</p>
<p>“I don’t think it’s that ridiculous to suggest women prepare food and the house,” said Kyung Jin Kim, 42, a former lawyer based in Seoul, who recently left her career to start a family. But she said the guidelines could have been more useful “if the tone were not so like a middle-aged Korean guy or an old Korean mother-in-law.”</p>
<p>“我不认为建议女性做饭、做家务有那么荒谬，”42岁的金京珍（Kyung Jin Kim，音）说。她曾是首尔的一名律师，最近放弃事业，开始家庭生活。但她说，如果“语气不那么像一个韩国中年男子或年长的韩国婆婆”，这些指导方针可能会更有用。</p>
<p>Under the recommendations, women were advised to check their household essentials so that their family members would “not be uncomfortable.” They were also urged to clean out the fridge, prepare meals and find someone to care for their other children.</p>
<p>这些指导方针建议女性检查家庭必需品，以便家庭成员“不会感到不适”，还敦促她们清理冰箱，准备饭菜，找人照顾其他孩子。</p>
<p>The advice made no mention of any responsibilities for husbands. But it did have some suggestions for how to remain attractive to them.</p>
<p>这个建议没有提到丈夫的任何责任。但它就如何保持对丈夫的吸引力提出了一些建议。</p>
<p>“Hang the clothes you wore before your marriage or small-size clothes you would like to wear after childbirth by putting one in a place you can easily see,” the original text from the site read. It added that “when you feel like you would like to eat more than you need to, or skip exercising, you get motivated by looking at the clothes.”</p>
<p>“把结婚前穿的衣服或者生完孩子想穿的小码衣服挂在容易看见的地方，”网站上的原文这样写道。它还写道，“如果你觉得想吃的东西比应该吃的东西要多，或者想放弃锻炼的时候，看到这些衣服，你就会获得动力。”</p>
<p>Though South Korea has become an economic and cultural powerhouse, many women still experience misogyny in very practical terms.</p>
<p>尽管韩国已经成为经济和文化强国，但在实际生活中，很多女性仍然受到歧视。</p>
<p>According to a 2017 report by the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, the gender pay gap in South Korea is the highest among its 37 member countries. Working women earn nearly 40 percent less than men, and many stop working when they have children, often pressured by their families and workplaces.</p>
<p>根据经济合作与发展组织2017年的一份报告，在其37个成员国中，韩国的性别薪酬差距是最高的。职业女性的收入比男性低近40%，许多女性在有了孩子后就停止工作，通常是迫于家庭和工作场所的压力。</p>
<p>Other countries in the region, including Japan — which also has an aging population and a low birthrate — have broad gender disparities, especially in relation to pregnancy. In Japan, the term “matahara” (short for maternity harassment) caught on when a woman’s claims of workplace bullying after she gave birth were heard in the country’s Supreme Court in 2014.</p>
<p>该地区的其他国家，包括同样人口老龄化和低出生率的日本，也存在着广泛的性别差异，尤其是在怀孕问题上。2014年，日本最高法院审理了一名女性声称在生产后受到职场欺凌的案件，“matahara”（“孕妇歧视”的简称）一词便流行起来。</p>
<p>These declining populations pose a threat to the countries’ economies, making it all the more important that governments tread carefully in incentivizing women to have children.</p>
<p>人口的减少对这些国家的经济构成了威胁，因此各国政府在鼓励女性生育时就更要谨慎行事。</p>
<p>Last year, South Korea’s population declined for the first time on record, dropping by nearly 21,000. Births fell by more than 10.5 percent, and deaths rose by 3 percent. The Ministry of Interior and Safety acknowledged the alarming implications, saying that “amid the rapidly declining birthrate, the government needs to undertake fundamental changes to its relevant policies.”</p>
<p>去年，韩国人口自有记录以来首次出现下降，减少了近2.1万人。出生率下降了10.5%以上，死亡率上升了3%。行政安全部承认了这一令人担忧的影响，称“在出生率迅速下降的情况下，政府需要对相关政策进行根本性的改变”。</p>
<p>Though the Seoul government may have fumbled in its advice, the backlash, some said, proved that attitudes were changing.</p>
<p>一些人说，尽管首尔政府的建议可能有所失误，但它所遭遇的强烈反应证明，人们的态度正在发生变化。</p>
<p>“This is just outdated advice,” said Adele Vitale, a birth doula and Italian expatriate who has lived in Busan, a port city on the country’s southeast coast, for a decade.</p>
<p>“这就是过时的建议，”意大利裔人士阿黛尔·维塔莱(Adele Vitale)说。她是一名助产师，在韩国东南沿海港口城市釜山生活了十年。</p>
<p>Ms. Vitale, who works primarily with foreign women married to Korean men, said that though Korean society had traditionally perceived pregnant women as “incapacitated,” she had increasingly seen their husbands adopting more egalitarian views toward childbirth and child rearing.</p>
<p>维塔莱主要为嫁给韩国男人的外国女性工作。她说，尽管韩国社会传统上认为孕妇是“无能力者”，但她越来越多地看到，她们的丈夫在生育和抚养孩子方面采取了更平等的观点。</p>
<p>“Family dynamics have been evolving,” she said. “Women are no longer willing to be treated this way.”</p>
<p>“家庭内的关系一直在变化，”她说。“女性不再愿意被这样对待。”</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>